

# **André Pedroso**

#### Tech Lead

@CEiiA // Centre of Engineering and Product Development In Engineering Product & Service Development Unit

## Profile

Tech Lead & Senior Software Developer with +10 years of experience. Team Lead, mentor, solution architect. I've been involved with SRUM methodology. Microsoft certified. Clean Architecture, DDD, CQRS, .NET 5/Core, ASP.NET Core, MVC, APIs, Swagger, Web Development, IdentityServer4, OAuth2, OpenID Connect, MSSQL, T-SQL, EF Core, Dapper, Serilog, Azure Portal, CI/CD, Docker, Kubernetes.

# **Employment History**

Tech Lead in Engineering Product & Service Development Unit at CEiiA // Centre of Engineering and Product Development, Matosinhos
July 2020 – Present

Tech Lead & Senior Software Developer at DevScope S.A. Porto

September 2010 – July 2020

Intern at Eufinity S.A. Braga

June 2009 - June 2010

## Education

Postgraduation – Information Systems Engineering and Management, Minho University, Guimarães

2009 - 2011

C.A.P. Initial Pedagogical Formation of Trainers, Actual Gest, Gondomar 2010-2010

Graduation – Information Systems and Technologies, Minho University, Guimarães

2004 - 2009

## Certifications

Microsoft AZ-300 – Microsoft Azure Architect Technologies 2019

Microsoft 70-487 – Developing Windows Azure and Web Services

 $\begin{tabular}{ll} \textbf{Microsoft 70-480-Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3} \\ 2012 \end{tabular}$ 

# Main Projects

CEiiA - IoT Hub of Urban Mobility

November 2020 - Present

Roles: Tech Lead, Senior Software Developer

### Contacts

+351 919 125 122

andre.pedroso@outlook.com

## Date of Birth

1985-04-20

## Nationality

Portugal

#### Links

<u>a-pedroso.github.io</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/a-pedroso</u>

## Languages

Portuguese

English

## **Tech Skills**

C# .NET 5/Core

ASP.NET Core MVC

**Entity Framework Core** 

Dapper/OMR

TSQL - MSSQL

**Azure Portal** 

Docker

Kubernetes

Web Services

**ODATA Services** 

Sharepoint

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

jQuery

**Bootstrap** 

ReactJS

**AngularJS** 

PowerShell

Main Technologies: MQTT broker (mosquitto, vernemq), Clean Architecture, Azure Portal, .NET 5, ASP.NET CORE 5, CQRS, Swagger, Serilog, Docker, Kubernetes.

#### CEiiA - DataHub of Ocean Data

July 2020 - Present

Roles: Tech Lead, Senior Software Developer

Main Technologies: Big Data. Clean Architecture, Azure Portal, Blob Storage, Event Hub, gRPC, Web API, ASP.NET CORE, .NET CORE, MediatR, AutoMapper, CQRS, FluentValidation, Swagger, Serilog, Seq, Loki, IdentityServer4, OAuth2, OpenID Connect, MSSQL, T-SQL, EF Core, MongoDb, DevOps CI/CD, Docker, Kubernetes, Prometheus, Grafana.

## FCPorto - Membership Renumeration

January 2020 - July 2020

Roles: Tech Lead, Senior Software Developer

Main Technologies: Clean Architecture, .NET Core 3.1, ASP.NET Core 3.1, MVC, APIs, Identity Server 4, OAuth2, OpenID Connect, MSSQL, T-SQL, EF Core, Dapper, Serilog, Swagger, MediatR, CQRS, AutoMapper,

FluentValidation, Hangfire.

#### **Gamobar - Portal Pec**

August 2019 - March 2020

Roles: Tech Lead, Senior Software Developer

Main Technologies: NopCommerce Portal, MVC, .NET, C#, Razor, AutoMapper, jQuery, Web Services, T-SQL, Azure, DevOps, CI/CD.

## Real Estate RE/MAX - Public Website

November 2019 – January 2020

Roles: Solution Architect, Senior Software Developer

Main Technologies: .NET Core, MVC ASP.NET Core, AutoMapper, Serilog, APIs, IdentityServer4, Azure Service Bus, Azure Function App, ReactJS, EF Core, Dapper, MSSQL, T-SQL, Elastic Search, Swagger

### BIT SONAE - Compliance & Audit

October 2019 – January 2020

Roles: Tech Lead, Senior Software Developer

Main Technologies: Outlook DLP, Exchange mailbox, Azure Portal, Azure AD, Function App, Web App, Microsoft Graph, ASP.NET MVC Core 3.0,

Bootstrap 4, jQuery, Dapper, Azure Database, API

#### BIT SONAE - Continente Online / NOTE! School Books / Wells

May 2018 - July 2019

Roles: Full Stack Software Developer

Main Technologies: .Net Core, ASP.NET Core, AutoMapper, .Net, MVC, C#,

Web API, Web Development, T-SQL, Unity (DI), Reporting Services,

PowerShell, node.js, SharePoint

## **SONAE – SonaeLink (Suppliers Portal)**

July 2016 - May 2018

Roles: Team Lead, Full Stack Software Developer



## **Hobbies**

Musician – Electric Guitar Player Main Technologies: SharePoint 2013, SharePoint Apps, MVC, JavaScript, AngularJS, jQuery, SignalR, Bootstrap, Web Services, AutoFac, Entity Framework, MSSQL

## Real Estate RE/MAX BackOffice

October 2015 - July 2016

Roles: Full Stack Software Developer

Main Technologies: MVC, AutoFac, AutoMapper, Razor, KnockoutJS, MSSQL, Service Bus, Azure Services, Windows Services, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, SharePoint, Web Services, Entity Framework, MSSQL

## **SONAE – Continente Online / School Books**

Mars 2015 - October 2015

Roles: Full Stack Software Developer

Main Technologies: MVC, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, KnockoutJS, C#, Web

Services, jQuery, MSSQL

## iWork RE/MAX

Mars 2011 – Mars 2015 Roles: Software Developer

Main Technologies: SharePoint 2007, HTML/CSS, ASP.NET, C#, JavaScript,

jQuery, jqGrid, Web Services, ODATA, MSSQL